<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<doc>

	<extension name="Collect">

		<remarks>
			<para>
				The <paramref name="changes"/> sequence is subscribed to first, followed by the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence on
				another thread.  This order of subscription avoids a certain race condition that could otherwise allow an element that
				no longer exists to be added anyway, without receiving a corresponding <em>Remove</em> notification from the <paramref name="changes"/>
				sequence.
			</para>
			<para>
				The <paramref name="existing"/> sequence is used to populate the initial state of the collection, under the assumption that the
				<paramref name="changes"/> sequence does not provide <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Add"/> notifications for
				elements that are considered to already exist; however, it may provide <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Add"/>
				notifications for existing elements after it provides corresponding <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Remove"/>
				notifications for those elements, thus the <paramref name="changes"/> sequence is processed concurrently while the collection is
				being populated by the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence.
			</para>
			<para>
				The <paramref name="changes"/> sequence is given precedence for all race conditions and conflicts while the collection is being
				populated by the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence.  This process is referred to as reconciliation.
			</para>
			<para>
				Reconciliation ends when either of the two sequences completes.  It also ends upon the first
				<see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Clear"/> notification to be received, because this indicates that there are no
				more existing elements.  The remainder of the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence is therefore ignored.  If the
				<paramref name="existing"/> sequence is still producing elements, then those elements must have been created recently and
				simply picked up by the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence due to a race condition outside of the control of this method;
				however, the <paramref name="changes"/> sequence is still expected to provide <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Add"/>
				notifications for these new elements, so they will not be missed.
			</para>
			<para>
				A well-behaving <paramref name="existing"/> sequence:
			</para>
			<list type="1">
				<item>
					<description>
						<strong>MUST</strong> provide a forward-only view of the source.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<description>
						<strong>MUST</strong> ensure that element positions within the sequence are unique and absolute.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<description>
						<strong>SHOULD</strong> finish observing all existing items and call <em>OnCompleted</em>.
					</description>
				</item>
			</list>
			<para>
				Therefore, if an element is created after the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence has passed the element's absolute position,
				it will not be included in the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence; however, a well-behaving <paramref name="changes"/>
				sequence will include it.  Furthermore, if an element is observed by the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence and then
				subsequently deleted and recreated, it will not be observed a second time.
			</para>
			<para>
				A well-behaving <paramref name="changes"/> sequence:
			</para>
			<list type="1">
				<item>
					<description>
						<strong>MUST</strong> generate notifications in a logical order.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<description>
						<strong>SHOULD</strong> provide a dynamic, real-time view that includes all changes to the source.
					</description>
				</item>
			</list>
			<para>
				An example of a logical order for the <paramref name="changes"/> sequence is to include an
				<see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Add"/> notification followed by a <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Remove"/>
				notification when an element has been added and subsequently removed.  An example of an illogical order for this scenario is
				to include a <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Remove"/> notification before an <see cref="CollectionModificationKind.Add"/>
				notification, which does not accurately reflect the state of changes to the source.
			</para>
			<alert type="warning">
				An illogical ordering of notifications in the <paramref name="changes"/> sequence voids all guarantees that the
				reconciliation process makes about the state of the collection when the <paramref name="existing"/> sequence
				completes, and also voids all guarantees about the active state of the collection thereafter.
			</alert>
		</remarks>

	</extension>

</doc>